你被监视着
You are being watched.
政府有一套秘密系统
The government has a secret system--
一台每时每刻都在监控你的机器
a machine that spies on you every hour of every day.
联系系统管理员
我设计这台机器是为了侦测恐怖行动
I designed the machine to detect acts of terror
身份不明
但它却看到了一切
but it sees everything--
身份不明
牵涉普通人的暴力罪行
violent crimes involving ordinary people.
政府认为这些人无关紧要
The government considered these people irrelevant.
关键执行人
我们不
We don't.
失踪
关键执行人
受当局追捕  我们只能秘密活动
Hunted by the authorities, we work in secret.
状态：纽约警局任职
你永远找不到我们
You'll never find us.
但无论是受害人还是行凶者
But victim or perpetrator,
只要你的号码被列出来  我们就会找到你
if your number's up, we'll find you.
第二季 第十九集
疑犯追踪
会话分析
语言识别
音频拦截
贾斯丁・李
科研技术部
高级工程师
贾斯丁・李已死  长官
Justin Lee is dead, Sir.
现在那名主管已经开始调查此事了
And now that executive has started digging into the accident.
根据我对她的了解  她不会罢手
Knowing her, she won't stop.
那就让她罢手
Then see to it that she does.
很有意思的一招  以利亚先生
Interesting strategy, Mr. Elias.
介意解释一下吗
Care to explain?
想学习在逆镜中取胜
Trying to learn how to win at a disadvantage.
看来我们谈的不只是棋了
I assume we're talking about more than just chess.
车和马  重要棋子
Rook and knight, valuable pieces.
地检官和舍曼斯基警探
The assistant district attorney and Detective Szymanski.
他们之死有利于你的敌人  彼得・约格洛夫
Their deaths benefited your enemy, Peter Yogorov.
很好  哈罗德
That's very good, Harold.
我了解到
And I'm in touch enough to know that
你里边的一些同伴
a number of your associates inside
最近被调到了别处
have recently been transferred elsewhere.
你在跟谁对弈
Who are you playing against?
俄罗斯人  HR
The Russians? HR?
幽灵
A ghost.
我非常想查清他的身份
Someone I'd very much like to identify.
这盘看来  大局已定
From the board, I'd say the outcome is a foregone conclusion.
别急着算我出局  哈罗德
Don't count me out just yet, Harold.
我还留有后手
I might have a few moves left.
代向约翰问好
Give John my best.
科尔
警方怀疑因交易纠纷
武装分子被击毙
已经开始想我了吗  芬奇
Miss me already, Finch?
这次可不是打电话找你聊天的  里瑟先生
It's not a social call, Mr. Reese.
我是要告诉你我们有新号码了
I want to inform you we have a new number.
我这就回去
I'll head back.
不要  你在跟的号码也很重要
No, you're tracking a number too, albeit a prior one.
-你继续  -新号码是谁
- Stay the course. - So who's up this time?
莫妮卡・雅各布斯  雷拉科技策略系统部高级副总
Monica Jacobs, senior VP of strategy and systems for Rylatech,
一家全美顶级的网络公司
one of the top networking companies in America.
安保很严
And the security is tight,
员工卡上都有无线射频识别跟踪芯片
right down to the RFID tracking chips in the employee ID.
那你怎么接近她呢
So how will you get close to her?
我找到了个合适的掩护
I've found an appropriate cover.
她是网络技术界的新星
She's certainly a rising star in the tech world.
忠诚的信仰者
网络博客和全国杂志上很多相关报道
Gushing profiles in blogs and national magazines.
一个来自印第安纳小镇上的姑娘有此成就很不错
Not bad for a small-town girl from Indiana.
技术极客  程序猿  听起来不怎么危险啊
Tech geeks and code monkeys. Doesn't sound too dangerous.
雅各布斯女士是亿万公司的高层主管
Ms. Jacobs is a top executive in a billion-dollar business
这种地方商业间谍最猖獗
where corporate espionage is rampant.
威胁可能来自任何地方
The threat could come from anywhere.
-今天安排如何  杰罗姆  -得快马加鞭
- How's my day, Jerome? - Let's go with slammed.
十点TOVO  十一点新技术会
TOVO at 10:00, new technologies at 11:00,
莫妮卡・雅各布斯
强制配对
花店打电话过来了
and then the florist called again
要确定李家的地址
wanting the correct address for the Lee family.
我们不理算了吧
Should we just let that go?
不  我自己处理
No, I'll handle it myself.
等等
Wait...
-这是新的中枢六处理器吗  -是的
- Is that the new Centra-6 processor? - Yes.
我还以为要下个季度才会出来呢
I thought they weren't coming out until next quarter.
它的可变数据处理跟传说中的一样快吗
Is its variable processing as nimble as they say?
我以为
I consider it
其在能量损耗和综合效率方面有巨大进步
a vast improvement in terms of energy consumption, overall efficiency--
我就知道
I knew it.
谁要说平板十六进制芯过分
Anybody who says tablet hex cores are overkill--
根本不懂利用中央处理器架构
Has no idea how to fully utilize CPU architecture.
正是
I agree.
认识你真高兴
It's very nice to meet you...
哈罗德・斯塔林
信息技术经理
哈罗德
Harold.
信息技术部有你真幸运
IT is lucky to have you.
我认为我们的网络解决提案本身已经说明白了
I believe our network solutions proposal says it all.
雷拉科技的路由器和交换机
Rylatech's routers and switches
稳定性高达99.7%
have a 99.7% reliability rating.
依据何在呢
On the basis of what?
我们五家竞争对手中的三家实施了独立检验
Independent tests run alongside three of our five main competitors.
我们的软件是自主更新的
Our firmware is self-upgrading.
其他公司也一样  包括中思科技
Like everyone else's, including Censatek...
人家点心还更好
who had better pastries.
你叫什么来着
Look, what is your name again?
罗斯・哈斯凯尔  研发部负责人
Ross Haskell, head of product development--
罗斯  我们的副总过来不是想听干巴巴的数据
Ross, our VP didn't come here to listen to dry stats.
我们为什么要用雷拉科技的产品
Why should we use Rylatech's products?
因为你们已经用了
Because you already do.
我们花了十五年的时间
We've spent the last 15 years
造出了互联网的主干网
building the backbone of the internet,
而我们最新的元件
and our latest components
将为未来的十五年设立标准
will set the standard for the next 15.
就连国防部
Even the Department Of Defense
都信任我们帮他们做数据传输
trusts us to get their data from point "A" to point "B".
不过  如果你想要一个理由
But, if you want just one reason,
马丁・巴克斯特
Martin Baxter.
他在父母的车库里创办了雷拉科技
He started Rylatech in his parents' garage
取得了今天的成就
and built it into this.
那种决心  我们都有
That determination, we all have it.
我们会永远为客户努力拼搏
We'll never stop working hard for you.
如果选择中思科技
Or, go with Censatek,
他们出了名的喜欢给网络高管提供高回扣
who is known for offering kickbacks to networking execs...
以及好吃的点心
along with their nice pastries.
你怎么知道中思科技的回扣
So how did you know about those kickbacks at Censatek?
我到处都有耳目  马丁
I have spies everywhere, Martin.
要是有人怂恿你跳槽
Well, if they ever try to entice you to jump ship,
一定要给我机会高价留你
give me a chance to match their offer.
我简直不知道没你怎么办  莫妮卡
I can't imagine how we'd get along without you, Monica.
干得好  罗斯
Well done, Ross.
铁尼  我听说你在查
Terney, I hear you're running point
舍曼斯基和地检官谋杀案
on the Szymanski and ADA homicides.
-是啊  -有线索吗
- Yeah. - You got any leads?
没什么靠谱的  不过我们在全线查了
Nothing solid yet, but we're pushing on all fronts.
市长那个受伤的下属  奎恩呢
What about the Mayor's guy who got wounded--Quinn?
他只记得凶手带了面具
All he remembers is that the shooter was wearing a mask
从后门逃出
and he ran out the back door.
-有消息通知我  -会的
- Keep me up to date. - Will do.
卡特
Carter.
只是打电话来问候一下  警探
Just calling to check in, Detective,
前来致哀
and to say how sorry I am.
我知道舍曼斯基警探是你的朋友
I know that Detective Szymanski was a friend.
谢谢  芬奇  我心领了
Thanks, Finch. Appreciate it.
要是有什么我能帮上忙的
If there's anything I can do for you...
我会跟你说的  回头再聊
I'll let you know. Talk to you soon.
我知道你不想跟我说话
I know you don't want to talk to me.
-但是舍曼斯基的事  -没什么可说的
- But look, about Szymanski-- - There's nothing to talk about.
除非你准备说出你线人的名字
Unless you're ready to tell me the name of your CI.
那人害死了他
Who got him killed.
-乔丝  -我说过了
- Joss-- - Like I said.
你没事吧
You okay?
比彻收到的舍曼斯基脏钱的线报
Beecher got a tip about dirty money on Szymanski.
我证明了那些钱不是他的  舍曼斯基就死了
I prove the money wasn't his, Szymanski turns up dead?
我得知道是不是比彻陷害他  弗斯科
I gotta know if Beecher set him up, Fusco.
-我帮你查查吧  -好的
- I'll see what I can find out. - Okay.
晚上好  里瑟先生
Good evening, Mr. Reese.
跟目标联系上了吗
Have you made contact with your quarry?
还没
Not yet.
你还在跟你的目标吗
You keeping track of yours?
是的  多亏员工卡里的芯片
Yes. Thanks to the chips in the ID cards,
我能看到这栋楼里所有员工的位置
I can see the location of every employee in the building.
发现潜在威胁了吗
Identify any potential threat?
到目前为止  只发现了过劳工作和生吃海鲜
So far, just overwork and the consumption of raw seafood.
雅各布斯女士非常敬业  热忱
Ms. Jacobs is dedicated, passionate,
技术精湛
technically astute.
你对这号码动心了  是吧  芬奇
You've got a crush on this number, don't you, Finch?
一个人认可同类的品质并不代表就
A human being can recognize qualities in another human being without--
她离开办公室了
She's leaving her office.
奇怪  我跟着她到了科研技术部楼层
It's strange. I followed her to the R&D floor.
她进了电脑库房
She's in the computer storage room.
贾斯丁・李
应该是在找什么东西
Appears to be looking for something.
找什么
Like what?
不太确定
I'm not sure.
仅供学习 禁止用于任何商业盈利行为
更多影视更新
请登陆www.YYeTs.com
原创翻译  双语字幕
人人影视
YYeTs.com
翻译：Nonopig  芒果妖怪  面条打包子  沙沙A  天朝直属
时间轴：烟幕迟迟   小萌   Jessie
特效&后期：灰灰是菇凉   翻译&校对&总监：阿好
为何雅各布斯女士身居高位
Why would someone in Ms. Jacobs's position
还要偷偷摸摸跑来偷取电脑文件
be sneaking around stealing computer files
还要躲着公司的保安人员
and hiding from corporate security?
我知道你喜欢那女人  芬奇
I know you like this woman, Finch.
但是中情局教会了我一件事
But if the agency taught me one thing...
最厉害的间谍
it's that the most effective spy
是不最招人怀疑的
is the one you'd never suspect.
忠诚的信仰者
A true believer.
里瑟先生
Mr. Reese?
里瑟先生  你在吗
Mr. Reese, are you there?
稍后打给你  芬奇
I gotta call you back, Finch.
你好啊  肖
Hello, Shaw.
我想你可能会在这里
I thought I just might find you here.
所以你就决定来拜访一下
And you decided to drop in for a visit?
监视很闷啊
Stakeouts can get a little tedious.
你怎么就认为我想要人陪
And what made you think I wanted the company?
因为我曾开枪射你  还是因为我曾把你们丢在公墓
The time I shot you, or the time I ditched you at the cemetery?
我顽强啊
I'm persistent.
也许你是领会不了暗示
Or maybe you just can't take a hint.
达琳・科尔和伊万・科尔
Darlene and Evan Cole.
你前搭档的父母
Your former partner's parents.
死去的搭档
Dead partner.
政府诬陷科尔是本土恐怖分子
The government framed Cole as a domestic terrorist.
我想你可能会回这里
I thought you might come back here
为他洗清罪名
to set the record straight.
你怎么知道的
How'd you figure that?
因为我就会
It's what I'd do.
主控者已经杀了他们的儿子
Control killed their son.
不需要再毁掉他们对儿子的记忆
They didn't need to take their memory of him.
即使中情局也不会如此恶劣
Even the CIA wouldn't stoop that low.
他们只会把所有见不得光的东西藏起来
They'd just sweep their mess under the rug
然后在墙上挂上他的那颗星
and give him a star on the wall.
你的前雇主因为科尔发现真相而杀了他
Your former employers killed Cole for discovering the truth,
没什么能阻止他们杀他的父母
and nothing's stopping them from killing his parents, too.
但你已经知道了
But you already know this.
所以你跑到了这里  而没有进去
That's why you're out here and not in there.
下次你想要呼吸新鲜空气
Next time you want some fresh air...
换个地儿吧
pick a different spot.
有位朋友曾经对我说
A friend once told me,
干我们这一行的
in our line of work,
我们行走在黑暗中
we walk in the dark.
但我们无需一个人行走
Doesn't mean we have to walk in it alone.
我觉得你这问题不像是病毒
Well, I'm not sure the source of your problem is a virus.
而像是
It's more likely...
摩卡咖啡
Mochachino.
我帮你换个新键盘
I'll try to find you a new keyboard.
谢谢
Thank you.
你偷的到底是什么东西呢
Now what was it you were stealing?
你在雅各布斯女士的办公室里做什么呢
What are you doing in Ms. Jacobs' office?
安全更新
Security update.
一周前刚刚更新过
We just had an update a week ago.
之后我们又发现了额外的威胁
Well, we've since discovered additional threats to the network
需要再次更新
that needed addressing.
具体是怎样的威胁呢
And what threats might those be, specifically?
一种复杂的内核模式木马
A complex kernel-mode rootkit
通过受感染的小程序来使得安全子系统失效
that disables secure subsystems through compromised applets,
我想就不用我向你解释
and I'm sure I don't need to explain to you
如果不安装更新是何等危险
how dangerous that could be if the update were not installed.
装好了
All set.
不用谢
You're welcome.
你想什么呢
What are you thinking?
纸巾用完了
They ran out of paper towels.
我是说你拒绝透露
I'm talking about you refusing to say
是谁给了你舍曼斯基钱的线报
who gave you the tip on the Szymanski money.
那些钱被联调局做了标记
The bills were marked by the feds.
在对以利亚的一家杂货店进行突袭行动中被发现的
Found in a raid on a bodega that Elias was operating out of.
所以呢
So?
那些钱没被收进证物
Money never made it to evidence.
要么是以利亚的人拿了这钱
So either Elias's boys got a hold of it
要么就是一些黑警干的
or some dirty cops did.
不管怎样  都挺恶心
Either way, it stinks.
你是说跟我有关
You saying I had something to do with it?
我是说舍曼斯基被人陷害了
I'm saying Szymanski got set up.
你一直不肯透露口风  让我觉得你也脱不了干系
And by you keeping quiet, makes me think you were in on it.
知道吗  我有个朋友以前也在
See, I got friends who used to work
你所在的辖区工作  弗斯科
in your old precinct, Fusco.
我听说过你那队组员的事情
I heard about your crew.
两个进了监狱  一个失踪
Two are in jail and one's missing,
你居然还敢说我是黑的
and you're calling me dirty?
我直说了吧
Let me spell it out for you.
-离卡特远点儿  -否则呢
- Stay away from Carter. - Or what?
这是怎么回事  伙计们
What's going on, fellas?
问的好
That's a good question.
这是怎么回事
What is going on?
贾斯丁・李
人事档案
雷拉科技人力资源部
我可以帮你做  莫妮卡
I can do that for you, Monica.
没事的  我都弄好了
It's okay. I've got it.
要我帮你买点午餐吧
You want me to pick you up some lunch?
不了  我有个会议
No, I have a meeting.
日程表上没有啊
I don't have anything scheduled.
是临时通知的
It was a last minute thing.
我就懒得列在日程表上了
I didn't bother putting it on the calendar.
-里瑟先生  你在哪儿  -在路上
- Mr. Reese, where are you? - On my way.
你发现我们的号码要干什么了吗
You learn what our number's up to?
我相信雅各布斯女士正要去交出
I believe Ms. Jacobs is about to hand off
一些敏感信息
some sensitive information.
莫妮卡
So Monica...
也许并非如此  你听听
Or perhaps not. I'll patch you in.
到底是什么紧急事件让我必须
What was so urgent I had to
取消午餐来这里跟你会面
cancel my lunch and meet you out here?
贾斯丁・李
Justin Lee.
他是你科研技术部一名工程师
He's one of your engineers in R&D.
是啊  一周前死于一起事故
Yeah, he died in an accident a little over a week ago.
悲剧啊
It was tragic.
我发现了件奇怪的事情
I discovered something concerning.
我给他的父母送花时
When I had flowers sent to his parents,
花商说没有姓李的人
the florist said no one by the name of Lee
住过那里
lived at that address.
可能搬家了  换地址了
People move, change their address.
我查过了  他的父母从未住在那里过
I checked. The parents never lived there.
不只如此  关于李的所有信息
It's not just that. Everything about Lee,
从联系人信息到工作经历  都是假的
from his contact information to his work history, was a lie.
我认为他是卧底
I think he may have been a plant.
卧底  为谁工作
A plant? For who?
所有的竞争对手都有可能
Could be any of our competitors.
所以我不想在办公室谈这个
That's why I didn't want to have this conversation at the office.
还有这个
And then, there's this.
她刚刚把昨晚那个闪存盘给他了
She just gave him the flash drive that she used last night.
我找到了李的电脑  拷贝了他的文件
I found Lee's computer, made copies of his files
发现了他死亡当天发出的一堆加密邮件
and found a handful of encrypted emails sent the day he died.
我试着打开  但没成功
I tried, but I couldn't open them.
还有谁知道这事儿
Who else knows about this?
只有你
Just you.
既然他在你手下做事
Seeing as he worked in your division,
我认为你会希望先了解一下
I thought you'd want to get out in front of this.
的确  我会去调查的
I do. I'll look into it.
然后我们一起告诉老头子  好吗
Then we can tell the old man together, okay?
莫妮卡
And, Monica...
谢谢你
thank you.
我得看到那盘上的邮件
I need to see the emails on that drive.
我得找个借口进入他的办公室
I'll have to contrive a reason to get into his office.
我有更好的主意
I have a better idea.
抱歉
Excuse me.
有你真好
Nice to have you back.
中央公园
感谢你能来见我  奎恩先生
Thanks for meeting me, Mr. Quinn.
肩膀好点了吗
How's the shoulder?
慢慢康复了
It's getting stronger day by day.
你电话上听起来很担忧
You sounded concerned on the phone.
舍曼斯基一案引发了诸多疑问
There's been some questions about the Szymanski investigation.
比如  我从哪里得来那些钱的消息
Like, who my source was about the money.
-你怎么说  -没说
- And you said? - Nothing.
你让我不说出你的名字  我照做了
You asked me to keep your name out of it, and I have.
问题是  我自己也想知道
Thing is, uh, I've been wondering myself.
那条线报是从哪里来的
Where did that tip come from?
线报很可靠  有什么关系
Well, the tip was strong. Why does it matter?
关乎一名殉职警探的荣誉
A dead detective's reputation is on the line.
就有关系
It matters.
卡尔  在我这个职位
Cal, in my position
会不断收到很多消息
I'm constantly being offered information.
人们愿意告诉我
And the reason people come to me
是因为他们相信我会保密
is they know I will keep their confidence.
好吧
Right.
线报来自以利亚手下的一名喽
The tip came from one of Elias's soldiers.
以利亚在坐牢  他的手下日子不好过
Since Elias has been in prison, his men have struggled.
这家伙不爽看着舍曼斯基拿着钱
This guy was just tired of seeing Szymanski getting paid
而自己入不敷出
while he scraped by.
我可以把那条消息告诉任何人
Now, I could have given that information to anybody,
但我想让我的教子领功
but I wanted my godson to get the credit for it.
我认为质疑你的人是想自己抢功
I imagine whoever's questioned you wish they had made the bust.
别为他们心烦
Don't let them rattle you.
没事了吧
We good?
是的
Yeah.
谢了  奎恩先生
Thanks, Mr. Quinn.
随时乐意帮忙
Anytime.
他会是个麻烦吗
He gonna be a problem?
希望不会
Let's hope not.
这么说莫妮卡不是间谍
So Monica wasn't spying.
她是在追捕间谍
She was hunting a spy.
也就是说威胁可能来源于
Which means the threat may be coming from
李为之工作的人
whoever Lee was spying for.
我已经让卡特警探调查他的死亡
I've asked Detective Carter to look into his death.
雅各布斯女士的手机好像在同步
Ms. Jacobs's phone seems to be syncing.
不是她本人做的
She's not doing it.
-那是谁  -好问题
- Then who is? - Good question.
他们正在添加捏造的联系人  预约提醒  通话记录
They're adding contacts, appointments, phone calls she never made.
里瑟先生  大事不妙了
Mr. Reese, something's terribly wrong.
不好意思  这是我的办公室
Excuse me, this is my office.
请你在这等着
You'll need to wait here, please.
这是怎么回事
What the hell's going on?
我也想问你同样的问题  莫妮卡
I'd ask you the same question, Monica.
但从现在的情形看  答案清晰明了
But by the looks of it, the answer's pretty clear.
保安在你的电脑上发现机密设计文件
Security found confidential designs and documents on your computer.
罗斯  我跟你说过文件是李的
Ross, I told you those files were from Lee.
那你为什么把它们加到附件中
Then why were they attached to emails
准备发给我们的主要竞争对手呢
you were preparing to send to our main competitors?
通话记录  会议议程
Phone calls, meetings.
你到处跟他们见面
You were meeting with anyone and everyone.
什么
What?
李不是间谍  你才是
Lee wasn't the spy. You were.
这不可能  杰罗姆知道我的日程安排
That's impossible. Jerome knows my schedule.
我应该早跟您说的  哈斯凯尔先生
I should have said something, Mr. Haskell.
她这段时间有些怪异
She's been acting strangely for a while now,
自己定日程表
keeping her own schedule,
修改预约计划
making off the book appointments.
杰罗姆
Jerome!
抱歉  莫妮卡
I'm sorry, Monica.
我不知道你要我说什么
I don't know what you want me to say.
-马丁  听我说  -莫妮卡  拜托
- Martin, listen-- - Monica, please!
-保安会护送你出去  -你要开除我
- Security will show you out. - You're firing me?
即时生效
Effective immediately,
保留民事及刑事诉讼权
with civil and criminal charges pending.
马丁  我为你工作了十年
Martin, I've worked for you for ten years!
那你应该请得起好律师了
Then you can afford a good lawyer.
请这边走
This way, please.
你  这是误会
You-- this is a mistake.
我什么都没偷  请让我解释
I wasn't stealing anything. If you just let me explain...
雅各布斯女士刚被雷拉科技解雇了
Ms. Jacobs has just been terminated from Rylatech.
看来有人想要让她闭嘴
Someone may be trying to silence her.
恐怕他们想要让她
I'm afraid they won't stop until they've done so...
永远闭嘴
Permanently.
早安  里瑟先生
Good morning, Mr. Reese.
雅各布斯女士有新消息吗
Any news on Ms. Jacobs?
有
Yes.
她在喝咖啡
She's having coffee,
就在雷拉科技的门口
right in front of Rylatech.
直觉告诉我
Something tells me
她不会甘心就这么被解雇
she's not taking her termination lying down.
我已经看过所有
I've gone over everything
雅各布斯女士所掌握的贾斯丁・李的信息
that Ms. Jacobs collected on Justin Lee,
麻省理工  工程师硕士学位
纽约州驾驶证
那名她正在查的疑似间谍
the potential spy she was looking into,
她是对的
and she was right.
李的伪装极为出色
Lee's been operating under a remarkably deep cover.
他麻省理工的学位
Take his degree from MIT,
毕业证书上的印章都是旧的
certified with a slightly outdated seal.
还有新泽西的出生证明  医疗记录
His New Jersey birth certificate, medical history.
伪造这一切的人
Whoever set this up--
非常专业
they're pros.
所以他们一发现她盯上他们后
That's how they were able to frame her so quickly
就能迅速陷害她
when they discovered she was on to them.
问题是  谁陷害的
The question is, who did the framing?
如果我能解密他的邮件  或许能有发现
If I could decrypt his emails, they might tell us.
她在跟踪她的助手  芬奇
She's tailing her assistant, Finch.
希望你没指望我下棋
Hope you don't expect me to play.
无意冒犯  警探  但我的对手
No offense, Detective, but my opponent is someone
得有更多的筹码
who brings a little more to the table,
而你却让我兴致寥寥
and you're breaking my concentration.
已配对手机
卡尔・比彻
那我直说吧
I'll cut to it, then.
有名警探叫舍曼斯基
Detective named Szymanski.
有组织犯罪科的
Organized crime.
他是你的人吗
Was he on your payroll?
恐怕你走错棋了  警探
Afraid you made a bad move, Detective.
我只想要答案
Just trying to get some answers.
那就问聪明点的问题
Then start asking better questions.
舍曼斯基被捕遭谋杀  谁获益最大
Who benefits from Szymanski's arrest and murder?
此人出手怎么做到未被怀疑呢
How could one arrange these acts without being suspected?
谁在隐身幕后
And who's at the center of the strings
悄悄操纵一切呢
that were quietly pulled?
我想你知道一些你不知道自己知道的事
See, I think you know something you don't even know you know,
也就是说  你在跟自己下棋  警探
which means you're playing a chess game of your own, Detective.
只是你还没意识到
You just don't realize it yet.
你给过舍曼斯基钱吗
Did you give money to Szymanski?
当然
Absolutely...
他把钱摔回了我们脸上
and he threw it in our faces.
他是清白的  你被HR耍了
He was clean, and you got played by HR.
见到你很高兴  比彻警探
It was nice meeting you, Detective Beecher.
给你一句忠告
Word of advice.
下一步棋走得聪明点
Choose your next move wisely,
否则就由不得你来走了
Or it's going to be chosen for you.
卡特警探
Detective Carter,
你查过李的死亡案了吗
have you had a chance to look into Lee's death?
我就是要说这事
That's why I'm calling.
他的宝马的黑匣子显示
His BMW's black box said
没有受到其他车辆撞击的迹象
there was no impact from any other car.
也没有刹车或者系统故障  单纯的事故
No brake or system failure, just simple accident.
我决定提取尸体上的指纹
I decided I'd take prints off the body,
看系统里面有没有记录
see what popped in the system.
指纹查到线索了吗
Did the prints tell you anything?
拿不到指纹  尸体消失了
Couldn't get them. The body's gone.
什么
What?
已经在停尸间找了45分钟
Searched that morgue for 45 minutes.
有人溜了进去  偷走了你们要查的人  李
Somebody got in there, got your boy, Lee,
凭空消失了
vanished without a trace.
我猜不是好消息
Not bearing good news, I assume.
比彻想追根究底
Beecher's looking for answers.
我们有人在里克岛监狱看到他
One of our guys at Rikers saw him,
去见以利亚了
with Elias.
看起来你和他的谈话没起到作用
Looks like your talk with him didn't do the trick.
真是遗憾
That's a damn shame.
我们可以把他调出去
We could promote him out of town.
到北部干文职
Desk job upstate.
我总告诉卡尔小心点
I always told Cal to be careful.
警察是危险的职业
Being a cop's a dangerous job.
昨天已经处理掉她了  行动不再受威胁了
-杰罗姆  -莫妮卡
- Jerome! - Monica.
-你来这干什么  -昨天发生了什么事
- What are you doing here? - What happened yesterday?
为什么要说那些话
Why did you say those things?
你在跟踪我吗  放手
Were you following me? Let go.
你不回答我是不会放手的
Not till I get some answers.
你现在可管不着我了  贱人
I don't answer to you anymore, bitch!
乖点  回答这位女士的问题
Now, be nice, and answer the lady's question.
说英语  别说普通话
In English, not Mandarin.
你为谁工作
Who are you working for?
你在浪费时间  我们人多势众
You're wasting your time. There's too many of us.
趴下
Get down.
-你是谁  -现在的话  活靶子
- Who are you? - Right now, an easy target.
里瑟先生
Mr. Reese!
-有新消息  -能等等吗  芬奇
- I have news. - Can it wait, Finch?
我破解了李的加密邮件
I've cracked Lee's encrypted emails.
是情报  汇报给他父亲
They're messages, reporting back to his father,
一名中共高层官员
a high-ranking official in the Chinese Communist Party.
你说什么
What are you saying?
李不是商业间谍
Lee wasn't spying for a company.
他是政府间谍
He was spying for his country.
我们挑起了和中华人民共和国的战争
We just picked a fight with the People's Republic of China.
你要带我去哪
Where are you taking me?
安全的地方
Someplace safe.
动用新房吧  里瑟先生
Let's use the new accommodations, Mr. Reese.
我马上过去跟你
I'll catch up to you as soon as--
被人找到的感觉不太好  是吧
It's not nice when someone hunts you down, now is it?
有何贵干  肖女士
What brings you here, Ms. Shaw?
我想你希望我找到你
I assume you wanted me to find you.
否则何必给我电话号码
Why else would you have given me your number?
我想着你会打电话过来
I guess I imagined that you would just call,
不过这样也行
but I suppose this works too.
我的提议仍然有效
My offer still stands, you know.
你觉得我得找点新爱好
You think I should have a hobby.
应该是什么呢
Now what would that be?
在废弃的图书馆里陪着你
Hanging around a derelict library with you,
你那社交无能的忠犬
your poorly-socialized guard dog,
还有小熊吗
and Bear here?
比起拯救世界是稍稍逊了一点
Bit of a comedown from saving the world, I guess,
不过也有欢乐时光
but we have our moments.
那你目的何在呢  哈罗德
And what's your end, Harold?
这是你的爱好吗
Is this your hobby?
经营半路之家  收容退休杀手
Running a halfway house for retired assassins?
我不喜欢暴殄天物
I hate to see talent go to waste.
天物特别信任你  是吧
Awfully trusting of you, now, isn't it?
我肯定  肖女士
I'm quite confident, Ms. Shaw,
你是第一个这么说我的人
that you are the first person that's ever said that to me.
另外  你也没拿武器
Besides, you're not holding a firearm.
看来还是有进展的  需要我帮什么忙吗
Looks like progress. What can I do for you?
武装疑犯传言是中情局特工
今天早上有则有趣的报道
Interesting story in the news this morning.
中情局的一名探员在执行秘密行动时牺牲
A CIA operative died in the line of duty on a covert operation.
他揭露了一个本土恐怖组织阴谋
He'd uncovered a domestic terrorism plot.
当然了  中情局永远是既不承认  也不否认
Now, the agency would neither deny or confirm this, of course,
但一名记者
but a journalist
收到中情局总部兰利泄露出的文件
received leaked documents from within Langley itself.
我也看到这篇报道了
I saw the story too.
真让人难过
It's very sad.
他是英勇牺牲的
He seemed to have died heroically.
你我都很清楚科尔不是中情局的
You and I both know that Cole did not work for the CIA.
所以我有个疯狂的推论
So I have this crazy theory
有人黑进了
that someone hacked into
全世界上最权威  最机密的组织
one of the most powerful, clandestine agencies in the world
建立了一名员工的档案
and created an employee who,
而此人昨天之前  根本不存在
up until yesterday, did not exist.
听起来有点牵强
That does sound somewhat farfetched.
酒店那位朋友
My friend from the hotel.
我们的谈话很快被打断了
Our conversation was cut short.
看来我们的共同点不少
Yet we seemed to have so much in common.
跟我说说她
Tell me about her.
我和这位女士的关系相当复杂
My relationship with that woman is rather complicated.
你对什么有兴趣
What's your interest?
你认为我该有个新爱好  哈罗德
You think I need a hobby, Harold?
我想我刚找到了
I think I just found one.
小叛徒
Traitor.
李是  中国间谍
Lee was a spy...for China?
看来是
Looks that way.
知道中国为什么会对雷拉科技感兴趣吗
Any idea why China might be interested in Rylatech?
我们的专利发明让我们
Our proprietary designs keep us
走在行业最尖端
at the forefront of the industry.
也许他们想偷走我们的设计
Maybe they want to steal our work.
或者毁掉设计
Or sabotage it.
李可能秘密修改了你的设计
Lee could've been secretly altering your designs,
使之失去功能
making them unworkable.
那杰罗姆呢
And Jerome?
可能是去监视你的
Probably there to keep an eye on you.
他当我助手两年多了
He was my assistant for over two years.
现在他死了
And now he's dead.
我们不会让你步他后尘的
We won't let that happen to you.
我们
We?
-雅各布斯女士  -哈罗德
- Ms. Jacobs. - Harold?
我本可以早点到
I'd have been here sooner,
但你的朋友前来拜访了
but a friend of yours stopped by
说那晚跟你聊得可开心了
to say how much she enjoyed your chat the other night.
等等
Wait...
这么说你不是信息技术人员
so you're not an IT guy?
不是传统意义上的
Not in any traditional sense,
不过这些问题应该暂且放一放
but perhaps we should set those questions aside
先想办法对付想要杀你的人
until we've dealt with whomever it is that's trying to kill you.
我怀疑不只是你的助手
Now, I expect that it was more than just your assistant
跟李先生同谋
who was working with Mr. Lee.
能把人安排到
To place someone in a division
科研技术部那么机密的地方
as secure as research and development?
此人必须有权限
They need someone with access,
有雇佣权
hiring approval.
科研技术部是罗斯负责的
Well, R&D is Ross's division.
李的事我只告诉过他
He's the only one I told about Lee.
我得通知警察  或者联调局
Well, I-I need to go to the police, or FBI.
-那正中他们下怀  -你被问询的同时
- They're expecting you to. - While you're being questioned,
他们会毁掉全部
they'll be destroying any evidence
能牵扯他们  还你清白的证据
that could implicate them or exonerate you...
除非我们先找到那些证据
unless we get to that evidence first.
禁止访问
雷拉科技
我的所有网络请求都被封锁了
All my network requests are being blocked.
你试过网页接口吗
Did you try the web interface?
是的  但我无法更改设置
Yes, but I can't access settings,
或改写RPC端口映射程序
or the RPC portmapper.
我来好吗
May I?
这可是我的心肝宝贝
This was one of my babies.
完全重建的接口
Completely rebuilt the interface,
禁用了端口映射程序
disabled the portmapper.
备用认证服务器吗
Secondary authentication?
增加了FTP文件传输协议权限和SNMP简单网络管理协议权限
Added for access to the FTP and SNMP.
你们两个要是想独处
If you two would rather be alone...
我把公司的系统建得无法被侵入
I made it virtually impossible to hack into our company,
而现在我却在要侵入
and now here I am doing just that.
整整十年
Ten years of my life.
熬夜加班  周末加班
Nights, weekends.
你知道我拒绝了多少邀请吗
You know how many offers I turned away?
现在这么忠诚的人很稀有了
That's a rare kind of loyalty these days.
事实是  我从没想过到别处工作
Truth is, I never wanted to work anywhere else.
那些人不仅仅是同事  还是我的家人
Those people aren't just co-workers, they're my family.
而现在他们都认为我背叛了他们
And now they think I've betrayed them.
马丁当时的表情
The look on Martin's face...
你虽然落了下风  莫妮卡  但并未出局
You may be down, Monica, but you're not out.
还没有
Not yet.
只要我能通过服务器的防火墙
If I can get past this server firewall,
我们就能找出
we should be able to locate the hidden network
李和其他间谍使用的隐藏网络
that Lee and the other spies are using.
-怎么回事  -电脑被侵入了
- What is it? - We've been hacked.
创建远程用户
访问防火墙
改写系统固件
他们通过破解密码侵入到电池
They've broken the password coded into the laptop's battery.
改写电池固件
改写了电池固件  退后  退后
Hijacked the firmware. Get back. Get back!
怎么回事
What happened?
他们禁用了控制电池充电器的
They disabled the micro controller that regulates
微控制器
the battery's charge.
一定有间谍在监控网络
Spies must be monitoring the network.
那现在怎么办
So what now?
如果无法通过防火墙  我也不知道了
If I can't get through the firewall? I'm not sure.
那同时绕过所有防火墙
What about bypassing it all together
直接访问服务器怎么样
and directly accessing the servers?
那我们得进到雷拉科技内部
That would require going back inside Rylatech.
-我可以指路  -太冒险了
- I could show you where to go. - It's too risky.
大楼里的每个人都认识你
Everyone in that building knows your face.
雅各布斯女士  员工卡你还留着吗
Ms. Jacobs, do you still have your employee ID card?
还在  但已经失效了
Yes, but it's been deactivated.
而且定位芯片
Besides, the locator chip
会告诉保安我的准确位置
would tell security exactly where I was.
我知道
Yes, I'm aware.
[ 警 报 ]
她无权进入
She's not allowed on the premises.
走
Let's go.
莫妮卡・雅各布斯
策略系统部高级副总
雷拉科技
前面左侧
Up on the left.
小熊  上
Bear, stellen.
雷拉科技
副总
策略系统部
上
Stellen!
逃啊
In here!
你们安全了  里瑟先生
You're clear, Mr. Reese.
找到服务器机房后通知我
Let me know when you find the server room.
我们进来了
We're in.
看有没有目录服务器
Now see if there's a catalog server.
目录服务器
Catalog server?
这儿
Here.
发射器装好了
Transmitter's installed.
他应该可以访问了
He should have access.
现在我连上了
Now I'm connected.
看看能找到什么
Let's see what we can find.
找得如何  芬奇
How we looking, Finch?
我找到很多可疑的高级加密流量
I've found lots of high-level, encrypted traffic
占用了相当大的带宽
using a suspicious amount of bandwidth.
我们在这待不了太久
We don't have much time here.
我竭尽所能快了  里瑟先生
I'm working as fast as I can, Mr. Reese.
有意思了
That's interesting.
-怎么了  -没事
- What? - Nothing.
我找出了接受这些流量的终端用户
I've located the end users receiving the traffic.
-你指那些间谍吗  -对
- You mean the spies? - Yes.
看来我们低估了
It appears that we may have underestimated
他们行动的规模
the scale of the operation.
包括超过半数的高级员工
That's over half of our senior-level employees...
每个部门都有
in every department.
所有改程流量都来自
All this rerouted traffic seems to be coming
大量的不同网络
from an unending number of networks
属于  政府
belonging to...the government,
军队  金融机构
military, banking institutions.
这些都是雷拉科技的客户  但怎么会
These are Rylatech clients. But how--
我们的路由和交换器
Our routers and switches.
它们被修改过  都留有后门
They've been compromised. They have back doors.
间谍不是在监视雷拉科技
The spies aren't spying on Rylatech.
他们在利用雷拉科技的技术监视整个国家
They're using Rylatech's technology to spy on the entire country.
上帝啊
My God.
他们到底是什么人
Who are these people?
里瑟先生  恐怕我们的侦查被发现了
Mr. Reese, I fear that our own spying has been detected.
你和雅各布斯女士必须马上撤离
You and Ms. Jacobs need to get out of there, now.
我太同意了  芬奇
I couldn't agree more, Finch.
雷拉科技
里瑟先生  你们没事吧
Mr. Reese, are you Okay?
我们没事
We're fine.
但楼里有他们的特工
But they've got operatives inside the building.
他们通过内部短信系统沟通
They're communicating on an internal SMS network
都收到了从同一地点发出的信息
receiving messages from a single location,
从罗斯・哈斯凯尔的办公室发出的
the office belonging to Ross Haskell.
哈斯凯尔的办公室在哪
Where's Haskell's office?
这边
This way.
里瑟先生  哈斯凯尔有件事你得知道
Mr. Reese, there's something you ought to know about Haskell.
他不在名单里
His name's not on the list.
哈斯凯尔并不是间谍
Haskell is not one of the spies.
放下你的武器  马上
Drop your weapon, now!
马丁
Martin?
马丁  是你
Martin! You?
我知道这像怎么回事  莫妮卡
I know how this looks, Monica.
像怎么回事
How it looks?
你是个杀人凶手  还是中国的间谍
You're a murderer, and a spy for China.
不  我只是在捍卫我毕生的心血
No! I'm just protecting what I've spent my life building.
你怎么能这么做
How could you do this?
经济原因  网络泡沫破碎时
Simple economics. When the dot-com bust hit,
我们破产了
we were bankrupt.
是热门收购对象
A prime takeover target.
而后机会出现了
And then an opportunity presented itself.
通过卖国来挽救你的公司
To save your company by selling out your country.
你他妈是谁
Who the hell are you?
这不重要  他说得对
That doesn't matter. He's right.
他是个白痴
He's a fool.
这世界变了  莫妮卡
The world has changed, Monica.
那些过时的
There is no value placed
爱国主义已经分文不值了
on outdated notions like patriotism anymore.
像我们这种公司
And companies like ours,
只有不断展望未来
we have to constantly look forward to the future
才能应对未来
so that we can prepare for what comes next.
什么未来
And what's that?
出卖信息而非捍卫信息吗
Selling information instead of protecting it?
控制信息
Controlling it.
因为控制信息的人
Because whoever controls information
就能控制未来
will control the future.
那这家公司所象征的呢
And what about what this company supposedly stood for?
伟大的美国成功故事
The great American success story.
人们喜欢故事
People love stories.
我相信它
I believed it.
当然
Of course.
所以你工作非常出色
And that's why you were so good at your job
所以你永远接受不了真相
and why you could never be trusted with the truth.
就像罗斯
Just like Ross,
死于名誉扫地的前雇员之手
one of several victims of a disgraced former employee
她闯进来  射杀了他
who broke in, shot him,
然后举枪自尽
and then turned the gun on herself.
里瑟先生  我已经通知了当局
Mr. Reese, I've alerted the authorities,
并且把证据发给了联调局
and I've sent the evidence to the FBI.
你的计划不会成功
Your plan won't work.
联调局已经在路上了
The feds are on the way.
-喂  -巴克斯特先生
- Yes? - Mr. Baxter.
你还记得我们
Do you recall our discussion
签署协议那天的谈话吗
the day we sealed our arrangement?
是的
Yes.
时间到了
The time has come.
你的家人会被妥善安置
Your family will be provided for.
我明白了
I understand.
里瑟先生  里瑟先生
Mr. Reese? Mr. Reese?
我们没事  芬奇
We're okay, Finch.
都不见了
They're all gone.
有话不能在办公桌谈吗
We couldn't do whatever this is at our desks?
这个  不能
This? No.
你给过舍曼斯基钱吗
Did you give money to Szymanski?
当然  他把钱摔回了我们脸上
Absolutely, and he threw it in our faces.
他是清白的  你被HR耍了
He was clean, and you got played by HR.
比彻在调查是谁陷害了舍曼斯基
Beecher was trying to find out who set up Szymanski.
也就是说这跟他无关  卡特
It means he wasn't in on it, Carter.
HR里的人利用了他
And that someone in HR used him.
我们得把这个发给内务部
We need to get this to IAB so they can--
内务部
IAB?
这可不是法庭授权的窃听
Not like this was a court-approved wiretap.
你想知道比彻的事  现在你知道了
You wanted to know about Beecher, now you know.
-要我说就放手吧  -放手
- I'd let it go. - Let it go?
弗斯科  你知道是谁给比彻那条线报吗
Fusco, do you know who gave Beecher that tip?
这你要问他了
You'd have to ask him.
卡特  比彻正在穿越雷区
Carter, Beecher could be walking through a minefield.
跟着他一定要小心
I'd be careful before I go and follow him.
他随身带着
He's carrying,
但不见兔子不撒鹰啊
but he won't talk to me unless he sees I'm fit to buy.
好的  交易结束时  我会进行突袭
All right, when the deal's done, I'll make the bust.
顺利的话  你拿一半
If it goes right, you can keep half.
-比彻  -你在忙吗
- Beecher. - Hey. You busy?
在工作
On a job.
工作结束后  请你喝一杯如何
When you're done, buy you a drink?
我们谈谈
We need to talk.
好的
Yeah, okay.
我现在在华盛顿高地
I'm in Washington Heights
不过我可以去第八局见你
but could meet you back at the Eighth.
我等你
I'll wait for you.
唐尼  你在搞什么
Donnie, what are you doing?
-我得摘干净  -摘干净什么
- Let me get clear. - Clear of what?
警官遇袭  枪击  重复  枪击
10-13, shots fired! I repeat, shots fired!
-卡特  -警探
- Carter. - Detective,
紧急情况  我们要联系到比彻警探
it's urgent that we reach Detective Beecher.
他和你在一起吗
Is he with you?
没有  怎么了
No. Why?
听到了吗  警官遇难  华盛顿高地
Did you hear? Officer in distress, Washington Heights.
华盛顿高地  卡尔
Washington heights? Cal!
卡尔
Cal.
走吧  卡特  走吧
Come on, Carter. Come on.
雷拉科技主管人员死于公司办公室
雷拉科技今日爆炸性新闻
Shocking news out of Rylatech today.
警方发现了执行总裁马丁・巴克斯特以及
Police discovered the bodies of CEO Martin Baxter
副总裁罗斯・哈斯凯尔的尸体  看来是谋杀后自杀
and VP Ross Haskell in an apparent murder-suicide when--
雷拉科技的股价
Rylatech stock
雷拉科技股价
受公司内部间谍传闻而大跌
plunged amid rumors of spies within the company's ranks.
联邦调查员已下令歇业
Federal investigators have shut down operations
并要求立即撤换
and ordered all Rylatech products
各政府机构的雷拉科技产品
at government sites be immediately replaced.
等候进一步调查
Further inquiries are pending.
我们忙着跟国际间谍对抗
While we were off fighting international espionage,
警探死于缉毒枪战
自家后院都起火了
things have gotten worse in our own backyard.
不管以利亚玩什么游戏
Whatever game Elias is caught up in,
情况只会越来越危险
it grows more dangerous every day.
雅各布斯女士  感觉如何
Ms. Jacobs, how are you doing?
不算糟  毕竟
Not bad, considering
我过去十年效力的公司
the company I devoted the last ten years of my life to
正在接受联邦调查
is under federal investigation.
拜托  我们可是一起破解了防火墙
And, please, we breached firewalls together.
叫我莫妮卡好了
Call me Monica.
你今后打算去哪里
So where will you go from here?
有几家公司想要我
Ah, I've had some offers come in.
我最感兴趣的一个
Though the one I'm most intrigued by
是家叫做IFT的公司
is from a company called IFT.
我听过呢
I think I've heard of them.
它们正在研发挺有意思的中央处理器架构
They're doing some interesting things in CPU architecture.
听起来是个好去处  祝你好运
Sounds like a good fit. I wish you the best of luck.
保重  莫妮卡
Take care, Monica.
你也保重  哈罗德
You too, Harold.
你会想她的  对吧  芬奇
You're gonna miss her, aren't you, Finch?
有闲情雅致再说
I would if I had time.
再说  我们还有件事要谈谈
As it is, there's a matter that we need to discuss.
我们闯入雷拉科技那晚
The night we broke into Rylatech,
我认出了间谍网络中的一些加密代码
I recognized some of the encrypted code in the spy's network.
它的手法
It had a signature
和斯坦顿上传的病毒很相似
similar to that virus that Stanton uploaded.
我破解了病毒代码  发现了两件事
I was able to crack the virus's code and learn two things.
洗耳恭听  芬奇
I'm all ears, Finch.
第一  只有一小部分数据
First, only a fraction of the stolen data
传到了中国政府那里
made it to the Chinese government.
其余的被传送到另一个组织处
The rest went to another organization.
我想就是他们给巴克斯特打了最后那通电话
I believe they may have placed the final call to Baxter.
我继续查了  但是只能挖出一个名字
I dug further, but all I could come up with was a name--
德西玛科技
Decima Technologies.
第二件事呢
And the second thing?
不管德西玛是谁  我相信他们制造病毒
Whoever Decima is, I believe they created the virus
是为了寻找并感染唯一的目标
to find and infect a single target...
机器
the machine.
不幸的是  我们不得不撤离雷拉科技
Unfortunately, we've had to pull up stakes in Rylatech.
雷拉科技
不过就像预想的一样  整个美国的焦点
But, as expected, the US is entirely focused
都集中于中国  而非我们
on China's involvement and not ours.
一个小问题
One small wrinkle.
破解我们加密网络的似乎是
The breach of our encrypted network appears to be
个人行为
the work of a single individual.
我会倾尽全力
I shall do everything in my power
查出他的身份  清除掉他
to determine his identity and render him irrelevant.
我们更大的行动
Our larger operation
当然  如期进行中
Is, of course, still on schedule.
设备渗透
信号编码